## NIKOLAS HERRON

TECHNOLOGY DEVELOPMENT MANAGER

704-664-0349
herronnikolas@gmail.com
Broomfield, CO
https://github.com/wolfpakk92

## **ABOUT ME**

Multidisciplinary engineer with several years experience in product development and process improvement. Seeking a career change to a more technology oriented career path to allow for further professional growth. Passionate and resourceful self-starter who has helped a start-up establish company processes that allowed the company scale growth ~10x.

## **EDUCATION**

## Front Range Community College

Associate of Applied Science in Programming (In Progress, expected graduation Dec 23')

2022-2023

4.0 GPA (CURRENT)

# North Carolina State University

B.S in Polymer and Color Chemistry (ACS Certified)

2011-2016

3.0 GPA

## **SKILLS**

Team Management

Product Development

Python/Java/C++(OOP Languages)

Web Development / Cloud Hosting

Version Control (Git)

Written Technical Documentation

\*\*Code examples available upon request\*\*

## **EXPERIENCE**

### Technology Development Manager Mar 2019 - Present

OSM Shield

Managed a small team to develop technical / system processes within the business to support multiple aspects of the entire company. Notable projects included creating and hosting a customer facing web application in Python/Django/JavaScript to serve PDF's and custom generated excel spreadsheets containing data for customers. Other duties involved consulting subject matter experts to aid in the development of commercial chemical product creation and writing safety (SDS) technical documentation (TDS) for our commercial products.

#### **Process Engineer**

Jan 2017 - Jan 2019

Meridian Specialty Yarn Group

Worked in a medium sized team of engineers to install and develop procedures for new state of the art dyeing machinery. Responsibilities included making efficient programs on embedded systems with a custom DSL (domain specific language). The newly implemented machinery and programs allowed for a 2x increase in product throughput and 50% reduction in energy usage.

### Laboratory Technician

Jun 2016 - Dec 2016

North Carolina State University

Worked in the NC State University Dyeing and Finishing laboratory to perform tests and services for both graduate students and companies that contracted work through the lab. Worked with several fortune 500 companies to treat and test textile materials through a variety of state of the art chemical and mechanical processes.